A creative and highly skilled HTML developer with 7.5 years of experience in designing and developing responsive and user-friendly websites. Proficient in HTML, CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap, Tailwindcss, and other web development tools. Strong problem-solving skills and a passion for creating visually appealing and functional websites. Excellent communication and teamwork abilities.

Skills

Frontend UI Development: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Tailwindcss, React.

PSD/Figma/Adobe XD/design to HTML conversion.

Responsive UI development with cross-browser/device compatibility check.

Custom UIs tailored to clients specific needs and requirements.

Effective solution for UI/UX feasibility on frontend.

Support for change requests.

Collaboration with design team and support for teammates.

Agile methodology and daily scrum.

Git for keeping source code.

Experience

SR. SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, VALUECODERS SERVICES LLP (A VINOVE COMPANY) - DEC 2021 - MAY 2023

- Worked for their client named FE Fundinfo (Domain: Finance).

Created pdf themes for their European clients using html5, css3, css grid, css flexbox etc.

Did responsive UI development for their web pages and financial urls.

Gave support to fellow team members for UI issues.

Tools used: Microsoft Azure DevOps, Microsoft Teams, Microsoft Storage Explorer, PDF Reactor, theme generator etc.

- Worked for their client named Flydocs India Pvt. Ltd. (Domain: Aviation).

Did responsive UI development for their Maintenance Control Centre module and classic flydocs

Implementing new features as required and provided support and maintenance.

Actively participated in sprints, provided input and suggestions for improvements.

- Worked for in-house projects: Cosmic Byte, Ania Management, Calcue and others.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, APPSTER LLP – DEC 2014 - DEC2018

Revamped entire frontend of apppster.com.au and appsterhq.com from scratch along with two of my colleagues and implemented animations and plugins using CSS3, jQuery and JavaScript. Worked as a product owner for few weeks.

Won QIII-Platinum Club 2016 for best project.

Collaborated with graphic designers and backend developers for best UX.

Implemented responsive and mobile-friendly web interfaces for their clients.

Provided ongoing support and maintenance for websites post-launch.

Followed agile development and daily scrum.

Reviewed client feedbacks on basecamp and JIRA.

DESIGNER, CONVERGENT TECHNOLOGES - MAR 2014 - DEC 2014

- Worked for their client named Samsung.

Created banners and background images for special events and holidays.

Provided support to backend developers for UI integration.

Created designs for their CMS and converted that into HTML.

- Worked for other clients like Apple, Eicher and NIIT.

WEB DESIGNER, SAGACIOUS SOFTWARES(NOW DIGITAL HIVE) - AUG 2013 - MAR 2014

Designed websites using Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator.

Converted PSDs and designs into HTML for clients.

Used Bootstrap framework, and jQuery for plugins integration

Helped junior web designer for UI implementation.

UI DESIGNER, WEBREINVENT TECHNOLOGES PVT LTD - AUG 2012 - JUL 2013

Learned HTML, CSS and started working on projects.

Learned Adobe Products like Photoshop and Illustrator for websites and logo design.

Started using jQuery for sliders and plugins.

Collaborated with clients to understand their vision and goals for the website and translated them into functional designs.

Worked on different projects with short deadline.

Education

De Montfort University, Leicester, UK - MSc Information Technology - 2011 BE in Electronics and Communications, Institute of Technology & Management, Gurgaon - 2008

Certificate

Namaste React Live Course TQVWC0AD - Feb 2023

HTML CSS Projects

Flydocs https://beta.flydocsuat.com/

ANIA MANAGEMENT https://www.aniamanagement.com/

Cosmic Byte https://www.thecosmicbyte.com/

Savvy https://savvyapp.com.au/

Open Charity https://link2pk.github.io/open-charity

Ebill https://link2pk.github.io/ebill

Treasure https://tresure.com.au

ABCBank https://link2pk.github.io/ABCBank

International https://link2pk.github.io/international

Fitness Time https://link2pk.github.io/fitness-time

Six8 https://app.six8.com.au

ConsultThompson http://www.consultthompson.com

RMR Marmo https://www.rmrmarmo.com

360 Degree World https://www.360degreeworld.com

Final Call https://www.finalcall.com.au

Streamhear http://www.streamhear.com

React Projects

Food Villa (Online food ordering App) https://link2pk.netlify.app/

Features: Restaurants Listing, Restaurant Menu Items Listing, Search bar, User Online Status and Cart Functionality using Redux Toolkit. https://github.com/link2pk/namaste-react

Video Streaming App https://link2pkyt2.netlify.app/

Features: Videos Listing, Video Watch Page, Video Info and Description and Related Videos Listing using Google Youtube APIs. https://github.com/link2pk/youtube2